Let's have a look at this rendering and updating process and where to place our pure components.
imdi bu ileme ve gncelleme srecine ve saf bileenlerinin nereye yerletirileceine bir gz atalm.
Consider this react application,
Bu yeniden uygulama uygulamasn dnn.
we have a root app component and then we might have a shop and a user's component and shop and users
Bir rota uygulama bileenimiz var ve o zaman bir dkkan ve bir kullancnn bileeni olabilir ve maaza
might very well be containers,
ve kullanclar ok iyi kaplar olabilir.
each managing their relevant state. These components probably also have child components,
Her biri ilgili devletlerini yneten bu bileenlerin byk bir olaslkla ocuk bileenleri vardr.
list and card for the shop and users one, two, three in the users case.
Maazalar iin liste ve kart ve kullanclar davasnda bir tane cretsiz.
Now the updating as you'll learn happens from top to bottom and only when state or props change,
Artk reneceiniz gncelleme yukardan aaya ve sadece devlet veya Propst deitiinde gerekleir.
so if the state and the shop component changes, list and card will probably receive new props and also
bileeni deiiklik listesinde ve kart muhtemelen yeni sahne alacak ve ayrca gncelleyecektir.
update
Eyalet ve maaza
and this also gives us an idea about what might be pure components and where this doesn't make too much
Ve bu da saf bileenler olabilecekleri ve ok fazla anlam ifade etmedikleri konusunda bize bir
sense.
fikir verir.
If we have lists and card depend on props which are distributed by shop, then maybe it makes sense to
Listelerimiz ve arabamz, dkkn tarafndan datlan sahne takmlarna bamlysa, belki de e maazasnda
implement shouldComponentUpdate in the shop case and stop updating
gncelleme yapmamak ve gncellemeyi durdurmak iin uygulanmas mantkldr.
if the state didn't actually change, if we maybe called set state but the properties in the state are
Eyalet, ad geen devlet olarak adlandrlsayd gerekten deimezse, eyaletteki mlkler hl eskisi gibi
still the same as before and then list and card won't be reached anyways so there's no need
ayn kalr ve nihayetinde liste ve karta ulalamaz, bu nedenle de gerek yoktur.
in turning list and card into pure components because we have a good check one level above them in
yaptk ve akas ayn ey kullanclar ya da uygulamanzn baka herhangi bir ksm iin de geerlidir.
our shop container and obviously the same would be true for users or any other part of your application.
Ve bir liste ve sepeti saf bileenler haline getirmek iin, maazalarmzda bir seviye stnde iyi bir kontrol
So having some containers where you have these checks might make a lot of sense and still you might
Dolaysyla, bu eklerin bulunduu baz konteynrlara sahip olmak ok mantkl olabilir ve yine de, konteynrlarn bu
even find cases where your containers don't need that check because you know you only call set state
kontrole ihtiya duymad durumlarda bulunabilir; nk yalnzca devleti aradnz biliyorsunuz ya da
or you only receive new props if they really changed. Then you can also leave out shouldComponentUpdate or
gerekten deitiyse yeni sahanlk alyorsunuz demektir. bileen gncellemesini veya saf bir bileeni de
a pure component
darda brakabilirsiniz.
but often times it might make sense.
Ancak ou zaman anlam ifade edebilir.
So this is how the rendering and updating works,
Dolaysyla, ileme ve gncelleme nasl iliyor.
how this tree of components is updated and handled by react and how you may optimize it.
Bileenler a nasl gncellenir ve tepki verilir ve nasl optimize edilecei anlatlr.
Let's now understand how react to optimize this updating process for us out of the box by not hitting
imdi, bu gncelleme srecini, gerek Dom'a her zaman dokunmamak iin kutudan karmamza nasl
the real dom all the time because as you could see, there is a big difference between the render method
tepki vereceini anlayn, nk grdnz gibi, arlan oluturma yntemi ile gerek Dom
being called and the real dom being changed.
deiimi arasnda byk bir fark var.
The second look at this in the next lecture.
kincisi bir sonraki derste incelenecek.